<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ed Leeman - #100DaysToOffload</title>
    <link>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ed Leeman - #100DaysToOffload</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 21:49:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 10 - Deleted docker-compose</title>
      <link>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/day-10-deleted-docker-compose/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 21:49:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/day-10-deleted-docker-compose/</guid>
      <description>Today, we ran out of space on a drive which was running an internal wiki. Unfortunately for us, we lost the docker-compose file which contained the database password used to get the data for our wiki.
Luckily, the container was still running, even if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t we probably could have spun up an old containers using something from docker ps -a.
As the container was still running, we exec&amp;rsquo;d into it with docker exec -it &amp;lt;container_id&amp;gt; bash and we&amp;rsquo;re able to run the env command which revealed the password that was set in the docker-compose file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 9 - Dabbling with Bash, public repository alerting</title>
      <link>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/day-9-dabbling-with-bash-public-repository-alerting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 14:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/day-9-dabbling-with-bash-public-repository-alerting/</guid>
      <description>I have been playing around with Bash over the last 24 hours, which has had its highs and lows.
I still don&amp;rsquo;t understand when to echo a variable into another variable and when to do a direct assignment. But it&amp;rsquo;s early days for me. I&amp;rsquo;m looking to take a more architectural approach to my day job, which means spending even more time in the Linux environment. I&amp;rsquo;d like to automate a lot of my repetitive tasks, reason 1 being that I save some time, reason 2 being that I will definitely forget to do the task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 8 - Our first sponsorship</title>
      <link>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/day-8-our-first-sponsorship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 15:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/day-8-our-first-sponsorship/</guid>
      <description>We got our first sponsorship on The Self-Hosting Blog , albeit, my parter! But it was a nice surprise and I didn&amp;rsquo;t ask for it! Even though it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t officially count, something inside me is feeling motivated, almost like it was all worth it, you know?
With the blog, we&amp;rsquo;re going to have a guest blogger. He&amp;rsquo;s Piete, over at https://www.pietersartain.com  who is doing some really cool stuff with Ansible at the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 7 - Blog Automation</title>
      <link>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/day-7-blog-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 20:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/day-7-blog-automation/</guid>
      <description>I have recently discovered that a lot of my posts over at The Self-Hosting Blog  follow the same passage.
 Introduction about the Software Provisioning your server Installing prerequisite requirements Installing the thing Configuring Nginx Port forwarding Certbot Recap  The only thing that really changes is step 4, maybe step 3 depending on whether Docker is required or not.
Why aren&amp;rsquo;t I automating this.
I think I know why, the content will be shite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 6 - Virtual Computing</title>
      <link>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/day-6-virtual-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 19:21:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/day-6-virtual-computing/</guid>
      <description>A friend of mine has recently set up his own virtual server. Which allows him to run 3 virtual machines on a single machine. He has spoken about it over on his blog . There are 4 parts to the series which go through picking the parts, technical challenges, and finally the end result. It&amp;rsquo;s a really interesting read, I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend checking it out.
He&amp;rsquo;s using Proxmox, which I have some experience with, but not to the extent of what he has managed to achieve with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 5 - Freelance Writing</title>
      <link>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/day-5-freelance-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 19:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/day-5-freelance-writing/</guid>
      <description>I’m starting to enjoy writing these blog posts. I mean, I enjoy writing, I just haven’t been very good at it. I often struggle with trying to think of an idea to write about, but I’m five days in now and haven’t run out of ideas yet! I think I’m finding my flow now. I have already met so many interesting people as a result of #100DaysToOffLoad. The guys over at Fosstodon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 4 - No Ads</title>
      <link>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/day-4-no-ads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/day-4-no-ads/</guid>
      <description>GoNads I decided not to put ads on the site. They make the site look poo and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t sit with me ethically. I did however make 30p which ia just about enough to buy myself a Freddo. Ads suck, in general, and as a source of income. They&amp;rsquo;re spammy, obtrusive and distract the readers from the content that you&amp;rsquo;ve worked so hard to produce.
So, I have made the executive decision not the run ads on The Self-Hosting Blog .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3 - Unifi Dream Machine</title>
      <link>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/day-3-unifi-dream-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/day-3-unifi-dream-machine/</guid>
      <description>The Dream Machine The other day, I purchased the Ubiquiti Unifi Dream Machine . A company well known by the guys over at /r/homelab  and /r/homenetworking . Ubiquiti have made a name for themselves in the enterprise world, but over the last few years, more and more homelabbers have taken it upon themselves to set up enterprise grade hardware at home.
Why did I buy The Dream Machine So for me personally, I wanted it just for fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2 - Monetisation</title>
      <link>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/day-2-monetisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 13:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/day-2-monetisation/</guid>
      <description>So, today The Self-Hosting Blog  got approved for monitisation via NitroPay . Which has got me thinking about where I would like to take the blog. I started the blog to be able to document my findings and giver back to the self-hosting community. When I was working on something that didn&amp;rsquo;t have much of a presence on Google, I would type up my notes as a tutorial to hopefully save someone else the headache that I went through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1 - Something New</title>
      <link>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/day-1-something-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 10:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://edleeman.co.uk/posts/day-1-something-new/</guid>
      <description>Hello Hello, this is my first post in the #100DaysToOffload  challenge. The brainchild of Kev Quirk .
I intend to use this space as a chance to improve my writing skills over at The Self-Hosting Blog .
I often find that I struggle to put my thoughts onto paper, and when re-reading what I have written, I feel like it was written by a 5 year old. I would like to improve how I come across on the internet and become a trusted source of knowledge to anyone who wants to know what I have to say.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>